## **CHRISTOPHER NGUYEN**

Portfolio: chrisnguyenhi.github.io | LinkedIn: chrisnguyenhi cnguyen7@hawaii.edu | (808)-343-7029

## AGILE | INNOVATION | GLOBAL CHANGE

A proven Scrum Master with technical development experience in leading complex large-scale projects that impact the world for NASA, IBM, and start-ups via undergraduate internships. Built a technical and project management reputation based on quality, flawless execution, and ability to deliver scalable solutions via "Sprint"/Agile process with the "Aloha Spirit."

## **EDUCATION**

## UNIVERSITY OF HAWAII AT MANOA

Honolulu, HI

COMPUTER SCIENCE MINOR IN BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION Expected May 2018 Comp Sci GPA: 3.9 / 4.0 Cumulative GPA: 3.8 / 4.0

## **SKILLS**

### **PROGRAMMING**

Proficient:
JavaScript • Java • PHP •
HTML • CSS
Familiar:
C • C++ • Python • Shell
Tools/Libraries:
Node.js • Express • MySQL •

## **PROJECTS**

#### HO'OKELE WAYFINDER

MongoDB • Ionic • Cordova •

Git • Swagger • Raspberry Pi

JavaScript, Node.js, Ionic Ho'okele is a Android and iOS app to enhance navigation and event-finding using crowd-sourcing & Google Maps. Won 1st at the Hawaii Annual Code Challenge Hackathon.

#### **PIPE**

C++, C

PIPE is an application that translates English-language sentences to C code for Botball robotics.

Best in Computer Science at the 2014 Honolulu Science Fair.

## **EXTRACURRICULARS**

- Alexander Hamilton Scholar
- AFX Dance at UC Berkeley
- Vietnamese Student
   Organization at UH Manoa

## **EXPERIENCE**

### NASA | Space Grant Fellow

Expected Fall 2017 - Summer 2018 | Python

- Building a cloud infrastructure for scientists to query temperature data from the NASA Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter to map potential ice deposits on the Moon.
- Reduced the runtime of I/O operations by 85% (6300 hours per year) using Pandas and Amazon EC2.

#### IBM | SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN

Summer 2017 | JavaScript, Node.is, HTML, CSS, Jenkins

- Automated the detection, sandbox, and build processes for 3rd party dependency updates in Watson Data Platform services in Node.js and Jenkins.
- Developed RESTful Express APIs to handle dependency version checks and documented them with Swagger for 8000+ Watson developers.
- Led a team of 4 through sprint plannings and daily standups as scrum master.
- Architected a blockchain solution to improve customer experience by validating the authenticity of ticket sales using Hyperledger Fabric.

## **OCEANIT** (DEFENSE ENGINEERING) | NETWORK SECURITY INTERN Fall 2016 - Summer 2017 | Python, Shell

- Acted as an IT consultant for a government agency to upgrade the existing Windows infrastructure to increase workflow by 90% for a \$30M project.
- Built a video wall system after prototyping and conducting initial feasibly tests which led to a 97% cost reduction (\$58,000 in savings).

## **DITTO** (BLUE ACCELERATOR STARTUP) | SOFTWARE INTERN

Fall 2015 - Spring 2016 | Node.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

- Delivered a social media platform with 200+ users for Android and iOS using Meteor in pursuit of innovating a new way to connect people.
- Led project to redesign HTML website and developed a data-driven approach using AB testing and Google Analytics which led to a 90% user increase.
- Followed the scrum agile development methodology on a team of 7 engineers, designers, and marketers, meeting multiple stakeholder milestones.

# **OCEANIT** (DEFENSE ENGINEERING) | SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN Summer 2015 | JavaScript, Node.js, HTML, CSS

- Developed an internal Android and iOS Customer Relationship Management (CRM) app using Cordova and Design Thinking to increase client engagement.
- Refactored an cross platform map app to support the government's ability to assess and respond to disaster (hurricanes, earthquakes, floods) with ArcGIS.
- Led intern school supply drive, raising \$300 for homeless children.

#### **HAWAII DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION | STEM MENTOR**

Fall 2014 - Fall 2017 | Curriculum Design

- Taught K-12 students and teachers C++ and JavaScript to cultivate STEM workforce development for the State of Hawaii.
- Mentored 2016 Intel International Science Fair 1st place recipient focused on improving Alzheimer's issues globally by imaging proteins on ImageJ.
- Recruited 30+ low-income students and networked them with external mentors.